Hyeonmin Lee

Network Security Researcher

• hyeonmin-lee.github.io in hyeonminlee1110

✓ min0921110@gmail.com

I'm a postdoctoral researcher at Seoul National University. I'm interested in solving security problems in the real world. I've performed large-scale network measurements to analyze network security in practice. Also, I've experienced diverse co-works with institutions such as Virginia Tech, Rochester Institute of Technology, University of Twente, KAIST, SIDN Labs, NLnet Labs, etc.

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea) Mar 2016 — Feb 2022 **B.S., Computer Science and Engineering**, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea) Mar 2011 — Feb 2016 Visiting Student, Information Technology, Uppsala University, (Uppsala, Sweden) Fall 2014

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher Seoul National University

Apr 2022 — Present

Seoul, South Korea

- o [TLS and DNS] Analyze how DNS can be exploited to reduce TLS handshake time (Achievement Publication [C3]).
- o [DNS and PKIX] Study how we can guarantee the integrity of DNS records using PKIX certificates (Achievement Publication [I-D]).
- o [Web and DANE] Study how the Web ecosystem will be changed if the Web adopts DANE protocol.
- [Email Security] Investigate how to prevent STARTTLS downgrade attacks.

Visiting Researcher

May 2019 — Aug 2019

Rochester, United States

Rochester Institute of Technology

o [Email and DANE] Analyzed DANE to measure its deployment in the real world (Achievement - Publication [C1, C2]).

Publications (Selected)

[C3] ZTLS: A DNS-based Approach to Zero Round Trip in TLS handshake (To appear)

TheWebConf'23

- o Sangwon Lim, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Hyunsoo Kim, Hyunwoo Lee, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon
- In Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference 2023, Austin, United States, Apr 2023

[C2] Under the Hood of DANE mismanagement in SMTP

USENIX Security'22

- o Hyeonmin Lee, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung
- o In Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2022

[C1] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

USENIX Security'20

- o Hyeonmin Lee, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung
- o In Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2020

[I-D] DNSSEC Extension by Using PKIX Certificates

Internet-Draft

- Hyeonmin Lee, Taekyoung Kwon
- o Active Internet-Draft, Mar 2023

RESEARCH PROJECT EXPERIENCE (SELECTED)

Research on Secure DNS and Privacy aware Packet Filtering Technology

Aug 2022 - Present

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- o [Keywords] Domain Name System, DNS over TLS, DNS over HTTPS, Packet filtering.
- o [Role] System Designer, Programmer I'm investigating a way to filter packets using the information in DNS messages and implementing it on BIND9.

Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

Mar 2021 — Nov 2021

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- o [Keywords] IoT network, network security, machine learning, abnormal detection.
- o [Role] Project Manager I analyzed IoT network traffic to distinguish abnormal traffic from normal ones using an autoencoder.

Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity

Apr 2016 — Dec 2020

(Funded by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP))

- o [Keywords] Edge/Cloud computing, Mobility, In-network caching, Trustworthiness.
- o [Role] Project Manager (Mar 2020 Dec 2020) / System Designer, Programmer I devised/implemented an ID Resolver that handles the mapping between IDs and resources in the edge network (e.g., ID allocation and mobility handling).

SKILLS

Tools and Languages Python (proficient), C/C++, Java, Go, Spark, Git, ŁTFX

Network Security, Domain Name System (DNS), Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP), Public Key Infras-**Quantitative Research**

tructure (PKI), Transport Layer Security (TLS), Internet of Things (IoT), Edge Computing

Communication English, Korean (native)